FOR THE SAKE OF LOVE
为了爱
EPISODE 1
第1集
Yu Ling.
Yu Ling.
Do you need help?
你需要帮助吗？
No, thank you.
不，谢谢。
Let me help you.
我来帮你。
So, I can say that I have been involved in a big interview.
所以，我可以说我参与了 一次大型采访。
I heard that Mrs. Yi highly recommended you.
听说易老师 极力推荐你。
You're our magazine's flagship journalist.
您是我们杂志的旗舰记者。
You have to do this interview.
你必须接受这次采访。
Yu Ling, the sales of the next issue will definitely skyrocket.
于凌，下一期的销量 肯定会暴涨。
Mrs. Yi has given me a very important task.
易老师交给了我 一项非常重要的任务。
I will try hard.
我会努力的。
You lost the opportunity to interview Shi Yan.
你失去了采访施言的机会。
Why are you still reviewing your interview draft, Zheng Shu Yi?
郑淑仪你怎么还在审你的采访稿？
Shi Yan might be an unusual guy.
施言或许是个不寻常的人。
I'm just checking my draft again.
我只是再检查一下我的草稿。
Some questions are too conservative.
有些问题太保守了。
Obviously it can be improved.
显然它是可以改进的。
I will perfect it.
我会完善它。
Are you okay?
你还好吗？
Is missing an interview making you crazy?
错过面试 会让你发疯吗？
Even if you have a perfect draft,
即使你有完美的草稿，
Shi Yan won't come back to you.
施言不会再回到你身边了。
I heard that the Editor-in-Chief called Mingyu Yunchuang
听说主编 叫明宇云创
and highly recommend the guy.
并强烈推荐这个人。
So, tactics are more important than competence.
所以，战术比能力更重要。
There are many important figures. Even though I lost Shi Yan,
其中有很多重要人物。 虽然失去了施言，
there are still other opportunities.
还有其他机会。
Having tactics can only get you one interview,
有策略只能 让你获得一次面试机会，
but competence can help you write good articles.
但能力可以帮助你 写出好文章。
Because I'm bad at tactics, I will continue to hone my competence.
因为我不擅长战术，所以 我会继续磨练我的能力。
It's a pity that you can't help me see what Shi Yan looks like.
可惜你不能帮我 看看施言长什么样。
Is he handsome or not?
他帅不帅？
Mr. Shi, interview with Financial Introduction
施先生接受 《财经导报》采访
scheduled for 19.00 after dinner.
预定19点 晚餐后。
Journalist Xu Yu Ling will come to the office to interview you.
记者徐玉玲将到 办公室采访您。
I don't think I'd choose Ms. Xu to interview me.
我想我不会选择徐女士 来采访我。
He is highly recommended by the Editors of Financial Introduce.
他受到《Financial Introduce》编辑的强烈推荐。
He said Ms. Xu is experienced in various aspects
他说徐女士 在各方面经验丰富
and the quality of the writing is quite consistent.
而且写作质量相当一致。
If this is just a question and answer, there's no need to meet me directly.
如果这只是一个问题和答案， 则无需直接与我见面。
Submitting an answer is enough.
提交答案就足够了。
Interviews should be like chatting and self-reflection.
面试应该像聊天一样 ，像自我反思一样。
I like Ms. Zheng.
我喜欢郑老师。
Sorry for my bad judgment.
抱歉我的错误判断。
I'll reschedule.
我会重新安排。
ZHU XING GUO'S OPINION ON THE CURRENCY WAR
朱兴国 对货币战争的看法
Mrs. Yi, do you want to meet me?
易女士，您想见见我吗？
Well, see you later.
那么一会儿见。
You don't need to comfort me.
你不需要安慰我。
I understand. I'm fine.
我明白。我很好。
Understand what?
懂什么？
I know you want to talk about the interview with Shi Yan.
我知道你想谈谈 石岩的采访。
I understand.
我明白。
Yu Ling is more experienced than me.
于凌比我更有经验。
Although a little disappointed,
虽然有点失望，
My interview draft can still be improved.
我的面试稿 还有待完善。
So, no need to regret.
所以，没必要后悔。
I'll prepare better next time.
下次我会准备得更好。
You're dressed very nicely today.
你今天穿得很漂亮。
Today is my girlfriend's birthday.
今天是我女朋友的生日。
I want to look beautiful in his eyes.
我想在他眼中看起来很美丽。
Looking from another point of view, if I interviewed Shi Yan,
从另一个角度来看， 如果我采访石岩，
I won't be able to celebrate with my girlfriend tonight.
今晚我不能 和我女朋友一起庆祝了。
So, this is indeed good.
所以，这确实是好事。
Okay.
好的。
What's wrong, Mrs. Yi?
易太太怎么了？
Yunchuang staff just called me.
云创的工作人员刚刚给我打电话。
They said for tonight's interview,
他们说今晚的采访，
Shi Yan has already appointed you
石岩已经指定你了
to do it.
去做吧。
Too bad, you're celebrating your girlfriend's birthday tonight.
太糟糕了，今晚你要庆祝 你女朋友的生日。
I guess you don't have time, right?
我猜你没有时间，对吧？
Shi Yan pointed at me?
施言指着我？
Yes, he chose you in the end.
是的，他最终选择了你。
Tonight.
今晚。
Do you mind?
你介意吗？
No, I can.
不，我可以。
Are you sure?
你确定吗？
Great, tonight at 19.00.
太好了，今晚 19 点。
Shi Yan's assistant will talk to you about the details.
具体细节石岩的助理会和大家聊聊。
OK, I'll get ready right away.
好的，我马上去准备。
Wait.
等待。
What about your boyfriend?
你男朋友呢？
Birthdays come every year,
每年的生日都会到来，
but the opportunity to interview Shi Yan was rare.
但采访石岩的机会 却很少见。
If I finish everything as quickly as possible,
如果我 能尽快完成所有事情
maybe there's still time to celebrate before midnight.
也许午夜之前还有时间庆祝 。
You are like that, Zheng Shu Yi.
You are like that, Zheng Shu Yi.
Mr. Shi, exclusive interview details have been arranged.
石先生，专访详情 已安排。
How about we schedule the interview in the main conference room?
我们把采访安排在主会议室怎么样？
Wasn't Le'an's representative scheduled to come ?
乐安的代表不是 预定要来吗？
for a meeting in the afternoon?
下午要开会吗？
Department One has already booked the main conference room for the afternoon,
一部已经预定了 下午的主会议室，
but they canceled it.
但他们取消了。
It seems they have rescheduled the meeting
看来他们 已经重新安排了会议时间
with representatives from Lieying and Le'an in the morning.
上午与烈英和乐安的代表会面。
Both in the morning?
都是早上吗？
Yes, the system shows it is rescheduled
是的，系统显示 已重新安排
personally by Mr. Feng from Department One.
由一科冯先生亲自指导 。
Fan, drop me off somewhere.
范，让我在某个地方下车吧。
I have to go back to the company.
我得回公司了。
OK, Mr. Shi.
好的，石先生。
What about Ms. Qin?
秦小姐呢？
Invite him and take him back to the Shi family's wastu.
把他请来，带他回 石家荒野。
Ya, Pak.
是的，帕克。
Amazing!
惊人的！
You've got the headlines for nine issues this year.
今年你已经登上了九期的头条新闻。
This has never happened in our magazine.
我们杂志上从未发生过这种情况。
Even Bu Yi's record is only eight editions in a year.
就连布艺的记录 一年也只有八版。
Do you still drink coffee? Do you want to be better?
你还喝咖啡吗？ 你想变得更好吗？
Drink this instead.
喝这个代替。
Why do you think Yunchuang
为什么你认为云创
suddenly change journalists for interviews?
突然换记者 采访？
This shows that their boss has sharp eyes.
由此可见，他们老板的 眼睛是雪亮的。
We mean, Shi Yan?
我们是说，石岩？
Shi Yan obviously had sharp eyes.
石岩显然目光锐利。
Otherwise, he would not be able to change Mingyu Yunchuang
不然的话，他也无法 改变明宇云创。
became a huge success in just a few years.
在短短几年内就取得了巨大的成功。
But he's also a bit strange.
但他也有点奇怪。
When Mingyu Group faced its most difficult time,
当明宇集团 面临最困难的时候，
he left his family's company
他离开了家人的公司
and start a new company.
并创办一家新公司。
What was he thinking?
他在想什么？
You don't know how cruel the rumors about him are,
你不知道 关于他的谣言有多么残酷
people call him the runaway prince,
人们称他 为逃亡王子，
selfish cowards, and others.
自私的懦夫和其他人。
Also, his girlfriend, actress Bei Lin.
还有他的女朋友，演员贝琳。
They said he immediately threw it away.
他们说 他立即把它扔掉了。
Actually, I think he's quite brave.
其实我觉得他还是挺勇敢的。
Despite all their doubts,
尽管他们有种种疑虑，
he still chose that path.
他仍然选择了那条路。
That takes great courage.
这需要很大的勇气。
What an honor for us
对我们来说是何等的荣幸
if you can establish a partnership with Lieying.
如果您能 与猎鹰建立合作伙伴关系。
Mr. Feng, you are too kind.
冯先生，您太客气了。
-We are family. -Yes.
-我们是家人。 -是的。
Appropriate. We've been friends for years.
合适的。我们已经是 多年的朋友了。
Of.
的。
Pak Shi.
Pak Shi.
Get two cold colas from the kitchen.
从厨房拿两杯冷可乐。
Ya, Pak.
是的，帕克。
I've been working on an article about Lieying lately.
最近我在写一篇 关于烈鹰的文章。
They said that Yunchuang is considering investment.
他们表示，云创 正在考虑投资。
You know about Lieying, right?
你知道烈英吧？
They have gained attention in recent years.
近年来，他们引起了人们的关注。
Many companies are willing to invest in them.
许多公司 都愿意对其进行投资。
There wasn't a single clear picture of Shi Yan on the internet.
网上没有施言的一张清晰照片。
He became more humble
他变得更加谦虚
and never appeared in front of the press after starting his company.
在创办公司后从未出现在媒体面前。
If we can record exclusive video or audio of him
如果我们能录制 他的独家视频或音频
for our digital magazine,
对于我们的数字杂志，
it will definitely attract many readers.
肯定会吸引很多读者。
Are you still thinking about upgrading your digital magazine?
您还在考虑 升级您的数字杂志吗？
Financial information is closely related to everyone.
财务信息与每个人都息息相关 。
If we don't fix it
如果我们不解决它
and stick to the same content as the print version,
并坚持与 印刷版相同的内容，
without effective interaction with readers,
没有 与读者进行有效的互动，
we will only fall further behind.
我们只会更加落后。
You're right too.
你也是对的。
But our magazine currently has no human resources or funds
但我们杂志社目前 没有人力、资金
for updates to this digital magazine.
了解本数字杂志的更新。
Even if you convince Mrs. Yi,
就算你说服了易太太，
he will definitely ask you,
他肯定会问你，
who will do it, how,
谁来做、 如何做、
and where the funds come from.
以及资金从哪里来。
I will do it.
我会做。
I want the higher ups to see
我想让高层看到
if I have the ability to lead the updating of digital magazines.
我是否有能力主导 数字杂志的更新。
Then, by monetizing the content,
然后，通过内容货币化，
we can get human resources and funds
我们可以获得 人力资源和资金
from the updated digital magazine.
来自更新的数字杂志。
What a bold idea!
多么大胆的想法啊！
Go for it. I support you!
大胆试试吧。我支持你！
You should stop by our place more often .
你应该经常来我们这里。
Of course.
当然。
-Hai, Pak Shi.
-Hai, Pak Shi.
This is a cold drink.
这是冷饮。
Thank you, Mr. Shi.
谢谢施先生。
By the way,
顺便一提，
I saw your latest data and information on my way here.
我在来这里的路上看到了你们的最新数据和信息。
-The progress is very impressive. -Yes.
-进展非常令人印象深刻。 -是的。
We just finished it last night.
我们昨晚刚刚完成。
Lily, please take Mr. Chen to the meeting room next door.
莉莉，请带陈先生 去隔壁会议室。
I'll follow soon.
我很快就会跟上。
OK, Mr. Shi. Mr. Chen, please follow me.
好的，石先生。 陈先生，请跟我来。
Pak Shi.
Pak Shi.
Mr. Shi Yan, if you have any requests, feel free to say so.
石岩先生，如果您有什么要求， 尽管说。
After all, we have a close relationship with Mingyu.
毕竟我们 和明玉的关系很密切。
Over the last two years,
过去两年里，
we also do business with your father.
我们也和你父亲做生意。
Of course, considering the circumstances at that time,
当然，考虑到当时的情况，
We definitely want to help.
我们绝对想提供帮助。
So, I'm sure
所以，我确信
we will work well together this time.
这次我们会合作得很好。
Mr. Shi, do you have any questions?
石先生，您还有什么问题吗？
Thank You.
谢谢。
I've reviewed the situation with Lieying,
我和烈英一起回顾了情况 ，
but that's what interests me more
但这才是我更感兴趣的
is the direction of your company in the future.
是你们公司未来的发展方向。
Our company is among the top leaders in this industry.
我们公司是 该行业的顶尖领导者之一。
As for Le'an Technology,
对于乐安科技来说，
they used to be one of our suppliers.
他们曾经是 我们的供应商之一。
This has nothing to do with position in the industry.
这与行业地位无关。
According to information,
据了解，
If your company's main goal is to serve the wider community,
如果您公司的主要目标 是服务更广泛的社区，
there must be further technological progress .
必须有进一步的技术进步。
But so far I haven't seen a solution.
但到目前为止 我还没有看到解决方案。
Mr. Shi, this is the problem.
石先生，这就是问题所在。
Lieying is a well-established company.
猎鹰是一家历史悠久的公司。
Investing in them will help us enter this industry quickly.
投资他们将帮助我们 快速进入这个行业。
Apart from that, Lieying has a close relationship with Mingyu.
除此之外，烈英 与明玉的关系也很密切。
We have gone through ups and downs together.
我们一起经历了 风风雨雨。
Correct.
正确的。
Yes, I understand.
是的我明白。
My father respects Lieying very much.
我的父亲非常尊重烈英。
But business is still business.
但生意仍然是生意。
The essence of investing is buying future value.
投资的本质 是购买未来价值。
If Lieying is willing to cooperate with Yunchuang,
如果猎鹰愿意 与云创合作，
You have to make a plan to upgrade your core technology.
你必须制定一个计划 来升级你的核心技术。
After all, we are an investment company,
毕竟 我们是一家投资公司，
not a charity.
不是慈善机构。
Don't you agree?
你不同意吗？
Thank you for your valuable time today.
感谢您 今天抽出宝贵时间。
Mr. Feng, please take Mr. Li away.
冯先生，请带李先生走吧。
Pak Li.
朴莉.
- Mr. Li. - Mr. Chen, please pass by here.
- 李先生。 - 陈先生，请从这里经过。
Technical breakthroughs take time,
技术突破需要时间，
but once achieved,
但一旦实现，
it would be a revolutionary boost to our domestic chip production.
这对我们国内的芯片生产来说将是一次革命性的推动 。
So, keep up the good work
所以，继续努力吧
and create our own patent.
并创造我们自己的专利。
I have high hopes for you.
我对你寄予厚望。
Yunchuang will provide you with maximum support.
云创将为您提供 最大的支持。
Thank you, Mr. Shi.
谢谢施先生。
If we can solve the research and development funding problem,
如果能够解决 研发经费问题，
I am very confident that we can achieve significant progress.
我非常有信心我们能够 取得重大进展。
I will visit Le'an again tomorrow.
明天我会再次访问乐安。
-We can discuss further. -Okay, I have to go.
-我们可以进一步讨论。 -好吧，我得走了。
Pak Shi,
Pak Shi,
I'll be straight forward.
我会直截了当地说。
The owner of Lieying, Mr. Li, is an old friend of your father and Mr. Tian.
烈鹰的老板李先生 是你父亲和田先生的老朋友。
If you insist on choosing Le'an,
如果你执意选择乐安，
I'm afraid it won't be easy to convince the council.
恐怕要说服议会并不容易。
Meetings are a fundamental part of investing.
会议是投资的基本组成部分 。
If you can't even schedule a meeting with a potential partner,
如果您甚至无法安排 与潜在合作伙伴的会面，
how can I trust your assessment of this project?
我如何相信 你对这个项目的评估？
Mingyu's investment is based on future trends,
明宇的投资是基于 未来的趋势，
not a personal connection.
不是个人联系。
Pak Tian.
朴田.
Mr. Shi suddenly came during our meeting today.
今天我们开会时，石先生突然来了。
Hai, Pak Shi.
Hai, Pak Shi.
(Uncle, didn't you promise to pick me up today?)
（叔叔，你不是答应 今天来接我吗？）
There's something urgent.
有急事。
(Uncle, don't you love me anymore?)
（叔叔，你不爱我了吗？）
Pak Shi.
Pak Shi.
I have to go. We will talk again later.
我得走了。我们稍后再谈。
I've put Ms. Qin.
我已经把秦小姐了。
He complained because you didn't pick him up yourself
他抱怨是 因为你没有亲自去接他
and asked me to convey his complaint.
并要求我转达他的抱怨。
Is there anything else?
还有别的事吗？
Yes, Mr. Guan Ji said he couldn't contact you by phone.
是的，管吉先生说他无法 通过电话联系到您。
What he wants?
他想要什么？
Pak Guan Ji held a dinner today at Warner Estate.
朴元智 今天在华纳庄园举办了晚宴。
He insisted you attend.
他坚持要求你参加。
I am busy.
我很忙。
Mr. Guan Ji had anticipated you would say that.
管吉先生早料到 你会这么说。
He said there was an important person he wanted to introduce to you.
他说有一个重要的人 想介绍给你认识。
YU YOU
YU YOU
OK, tell him I'll come tonight.
好吧，告诉他 我今晚就来。
How about tonight's Financial Introduction interview?
今晚的金融介绍采访怎么样？
Explain the situation to them and reschedule.
向他们解释情况 并重新安排。
Fine, I'll do it right away.
好的，我马上去做。
(Honey, you're not working overtime today, are you?)
（亲爱的，你今天没有加班吧？）
Xing Zhou,
Xing Zhou,
do you remember the interview with Shi Yan that I told you about?
你还记得我跟你说过的对石岩的采访吗？
Bu Yi just told me
布易刚刚告诉我
if they have changed journalists
如果他们更换了记者
to interview Shi Yan. I'm doing it now.
采访石岩。 我现在正在做。
(But my birthday is only once a year.)
（但我的生日 每年只有一次。）
I'm sorry, Xing Zhou.
对不起，周星。
I've been preparing for this interview for over two months.
为了这次面试我已经准备了 两个多月了。
This is truly a rare opportunity.
这确实是一个难得的机会。
He asked me specifically.
他特意问我。
If I don't come, we won't have a headline for the next issue.
如果我不来，我们就没有 下一期的头条新闻。
You know how many stories he has.
你知道他有多少故事 。
He hasn't done any interviews since founding Mingyu Yunchuang.
自从创立明宇云创以来，他就没有接受过任何采访
This will be his first exclusive interview.
这将是 他的第一次独家专访。
(Alright. I guess we can celebrate later.)
（好吧。我想我们可以 稍后庆祝。）
(I'll wait for you downstairs after my work is finished.)
（我工作完成后在楼下等你。）
I'm sorry, Xing Zhou.
对不起，周星。
This is very sudden.
这件事非常突然。
(I understand.)
（我明白。）
(You've done a lot of preparation for this interview.)
（你为这次采访做了很多准备 。）
(You should make the most of it .)
（你应该充分利用它
Thank you, Xing Zhou.
谢谢周星。
You are the best.
你是最棒的。
Interviews start at 19.00.
面试于 19 点开始。
I'll try to finish it within two hours.
我会尽力在两个小时内完成它。
There's still time to see you, blow out the candles, make a wish,
还有时间去看你， 吹灭蜡烛，许愿，
and enjoy birthday cake.
并享受生日蛋糕。
(I'll come pick you up later.)
（我稍后会来接你。）
I'll send you my location later.
稍后我会把我的位置发给你。
You are so kind.
你真好。
So, your boyfriend doesn't mind?
那么，你男朋友不介意吗？
Yes, he understood and even offered to pick me up.
是的，他理解了，甚至主动提出 来接我。
Your boyfriend seems too understanding.
看来你男朋友太善解人意了。
Unlike my boyfriend, he is very possessive.
与我男朋友不同， 他占有欲很强。
If I cancel my promise just once,
如果我只取消一次承诺
whatever the reason, he will be angry with me.
不管出于什么原因， 他都会生我的气。
Let's go.
我们走吧。
(Halo, Nn. Zheng. Aku Chen Sheng dari Mingyu Yunchuang.)
(Halo, Nn. Zheng. Aku Chen Sheng dari Mingyu Yunchuang.)
Hello Pak Chen.
陈柏你好。
Ms. Zheng, Mr. Shi has to cancel
Ms. Zheng, Mr. Shi has to cancel
interview tonight for personal reasons.
由于个人原因今晚面试。
We need to reschedule.
我们需要重新安排。
(We are very sorry.)
（我们很抱歉。）
What day does Mr. Shi want to reschedule the interview?
石先生想改期面试哪一天？
(How about the same day next week?)
（下周同一天怎么样？）
(Or is there a convenient time for you next week?)
（或者 下周你方便吗？）
If we reschedule for next week,
如果我们重新安排 下周的话
We don't have a headline for the next issue.
我们没有 下一期的标题。
Can Mr. Shi spare some time in the next two days?
石先生 这两天能抽出时间吗？
The timing is not a problem.
时机不是问题。
We can even divide it into two sessions.
我们甚至可以把它 分成两个部分。
I think that's impossible.
我认为那是不可能的。
(Mr Shi's schedule for the next two days is already full.)
（史先生 这两天的行程已经排满了。）
So...
所以...
How about spending two hours tonight?
今晚花两个小时怎么样 ？
One hour is not a problem.
一小时不是问题。
Mr. Shi has personal matters tonight.
石先生今晚有私人事务。
He couldn't spare the time.
他抽不出时间。
(We're really sorry.)
（我们真的很抱歉。）
Wait...
等待...
Shan Shan, you are beautiful and have many connections.
杉杉，你很漂亮 ，人脉也很多。
Can you help me find out where Shi Yan will be tonight?
你能帮我查一下 施言今晚会在哪里吗？
Halo.
光环。
Shi Yan?
Shi Yan?
I don't know him.
我不认识他。
But you're lucky.
但你很幸运。
(I know Shi Yan's good friend, Guan Ji,)
（我认识石岩的好朋友管吉，）
(holding a private banquet at Warner Estate tonight.)
（今晚在华纳庄园举行私人宴会。）
(I think there are many people in Jiangcheng)
（我觉得江城人很多）
(Those with connections to Guan Capital will attend.)
（与冠资本有关系的人士将出席。）
(I'm not sure if Shi Yan will be there.)
（不知道 石岩会不会在。）
Well then, I'll try my luck.
好吧，那 我就试试运气吧。
(Wait.)
（等待。）
(Aren't you supposed to celebrate)
（你不是应该庆祝一下吗）
(Yue Xing Zhou's birthday tonight?)
（今晚周月星生日？）
(You're going to cancel?)
（你要取消吗？）
I can't miss Shi Yan, right?
我不能错过施言吧？
(Okay.)
（好的。）
(Career-focused women are the most charming.)
（事业心强的女人 最有魅力。）
Thank you for your kind words.
感谢您的客气话。
Warner Estate.
华纳庄园。
Enjoy.
享受。
Come here.
过来。
Mr. Chen, good evening.
陈先生，晚上好。
I'm at Warner Estate now.
我现在在华纳庄园。
(Ms. Zheng, how did you...)
（郑小姐，你怎么……）
I'm sorry for coming uninvited,
很抱歉 不请自来
but this is an urgent matter.
但这是一件紧急的事情。
Can you tell Mr. Shi that I can wait for him here?
你能告诉石先生 我可以在这里等他吗？
Hopefully he can feel my sincerity
希望他能感受到我的诚意
and make time for interviews.
并腾出时间进行采访。
That's it, find a place and wait.
就这样， 找个地方等着吧。
I'll talk to Mr. Shi,
我去跟史先生谈谈
but I can't guarantee that he will have time to meet you.
但我不能保证他有时间 见到你。
(Most likely you came here in vain.)
（很可能 你是白来的。）
I understand. Whatever happens, I am very grateful to you.
我明白。无论发生什么， 我都非常感谢你。
I think Guan Ji held this banquet
我认为这场宴会是管吉举办的
for everyone to eat and drink.
供大家吃喝。
It can't be that simple.
事情不可能那么简单。
Kudengar Yu You
Kudengar Yu You
specially recruited by Guan Capital from abroad.
冠峰资本特意从国外招募。
He is a professor at the University of Finance and Economics.
现任财经大学教授。
Only Guan Capital has the power
只有冠资本有实力
to hire him as a consultant.
聘请他 作为顾问。
I see his son Shi is also here.
我看他的儿子施也在这里。
Shi Wen Guang's son was very unreliable.
施文光的儿子 很不靠谱。
When Mingyu was in trouble, he started his own company.
当明玉陷入困境时， 他创办了自己的公司。
Shi Wen Guang was forced to entrust the company
施文光 被迫委托公司
to his son-in-law and those outsiders.
对他的女婿和那些外人来说。
Exaggeration.
夸张。
From what I see, two young men from the Guan and Shi families
据我所知， 关氏和石家的两个年轻人
quite ambitious.
相当雄心勃勃。
By bringing professors from abroad,
通过引进 国外教授，
they might be planning to make a breakthrough.
他们可能正计划 取得突破。
One is shy and the other likes to have fun.
一个害羞，另一个 喜欢玩乐。
What breakthroughs can they make?
他们能取得哪些突破？
It is impossible. Come on.
是不可能的。快点。
Is Guan Ji late again?
管吉又迟到了吗？
Mr. Guan Ji said he was stuck in traffic,
管吉先生说 他堵车了，
but it will be here in ten minutes.
但十分钟后就会到了 。
Is there anything else?
还有别的事吗？
Ms. Zheng from Financial Introduction is also here.
财经介绍的郑女士 也来了。
He said he would wait for you
他说他会等你
and hope you can find time to do an interview tonight.
希望您 今晚能抽出时间接受采访。
Zheng Shu Yi?
Zheng Shu Yi?
Didn't I ask to reschedule?
我不是要求 重新安排吗？
I've told him,
我已经告诉他，
but he said that the interview was cancelled,
但他说 采访取消了，
The next issue of the magazine had no headline.
该杂志的下一期 没有标题。
I don't know how he knows about your personal schedule.
我不知道他怎么知道 你的个人日程安排。
I have a meeting at Le'an Technology tomorrow,
明天我在乐安科技开会，
so I don't have time for an interview tonight.
所以今晚我没有时间 接受采访。
Since he came all the way here, probably hasn't eaten yet.
他大老远来到这里， 估计还没有吃饭。
Prepare food and a car to take him home.
准备食物和汽车 送他回家。
It's hard to get a taxi here.
这里很难叫到出租车。
Ya, Pak Shi.
Ya, Pak Shi.
Graduated from Harvard University with a full scholarship.
以全额奖学金毕业于哈佛大学。
Double PhD degree in Economics and Finance from Cambridge University!
剑桥大学经济与金融双博士学位！
Soon became the youngest professor at the University of Finance and Economics.
很快成为财经大学最年轻的教授。
Impressive resume.
令人印象深刻的简历。
-Thank You. -You're welcome.
-谢谢。 -不客气。
Wait.
等待。
Are you Yu You? Professor Yu?
你是于佑吗？于教授？
You know me?
你了解我？
I've read some of your papers.
我读过你的一些论文。
Financial technology, technology-based financial innovation,
金融科技， 以科技为基础的金融创新，
not only has an impact on macroeconomics,
不仅影响宏观经济，
also has the potential to bring major changes to our daily lives.
也有可能 给我们的日常生活带来重大改变。
I feel a close connection to this field
我感觉与这个领域有着密切的联系
because it is very relevant to everyday life.
因为它与日常生活息息相关。
Correct. That is also the reason I chose this research direction.
正确的。这也是我选择这个研究方向的原因 。
In the past, finance and capital seemed like a luxurious concept,
过去，金融和资本 似乎是一个奢侈的概念，
but now we are exploring
但现在我们正在探索
how it can change our life to what extent.
它如何能够在多大程度上改变我们的生活。
If you have the chance,
如果有机会的话，
I want to return to my alma mater
我想回到我的母校
and attended some of your lectures, Professor Yu.
并听过于教授您的一些讲座。
Are you a graduate of the University of Finance and Economics?
您是财经大学毕业生吗？
Yes, currently I work at Financial Introduction.
是的，目前我 在 Financial Intro 工作。
I'm a journalist.
我是一名记者。
Professor Yu, can we be friends on WeChat?
于教授， 我们可以加个微信好友吗？
- Mr. Shi. -Of course.
- 石先生。 -当然。
-I'll scan your code. -Good.
-我会扫描你的代码。 -好的。
Itu Zheng Shu Yi dari Financial Introduce.
Itu Zheng Shu Yi dari Financial Introduce.
Finished.
完成的。
Zheng Shu Yi. I'll put "journalist".
郑淑仪. 我会加上“记者”。
Thank You.
谢谢。
Zheng Shu Yi?
Zheng Shu Yi?
Winner of Best Journalist this year
今年最佳记者获得者
is an article journalist
是一名文章记者
"Zhu Xing Guo's Opinion on the Currency War,"
《朱兴国 对货币战争的看法》
Zheng Shu Yi.
Zheng Shu Yi.
Excuse me. I'm late.
打扰一下。我来晚了。
Guan Ji, it's been a long time since you rode a horse with me.
管吉，你好久没有 跟我一起骑马了。
My fault.
我的错。
I heard you went to Qionghai, so I waited for you to come back.
听说你去了琼海， 所以我等你回来。
I'm back now.
我现在回来了。
Then, I will wait for you at the equestrian club tomorrow.
那么，明天我在马术俱乐部等你。
As far as I know,
据我所知，
Tonight's banquet is not open to the media.
今晚的宴会 不对媒体开放。
Yes, I came personally to wait for the interviewee.
是的，我亲自来 等待面试者的。
Work is important, and so is your health.
工作很重要， 健康也很重要。
You don't look well.
你看起来不太好。
No, I'll be fine after taking the medicine.
不用了，吃完药就没事了。
We went in first.
我们先进去了。
Of.
的。
I have to go.
我得走了。
Come in.
进来。
Pak Shi!
Pak Shi!
Sorry, Ms. Zheng. Mr. Shi really doesn't have time tonight,
对不起，郑女士。石先生 今晚确实没有时间，
but I will arrange an interview as soon as possible.
但我会 尽快安排面试。
You haven't had dinner yet, have you?
你还没吃晚饭吧？
Please eat first
请先吃饭
and I will prepare a car to take you home.
我会准备一辆车 送你回家。
It doesn't matter. Someone picked me up.
没关系。有人接我了。
I almost succeeded.
我差一点就成功了。
At least, let me see what you look like.
至少，让我看看 你长什么样子吧。
-Long time no see. -Yes, that's right, Mr. Zhang.
-好久不见。 -是的，没错，张先生。
-Pleased to meet you.
-很高兴认识你。
Mr. Wang, how are you?
王先生，你好吗？
Hello, Professor Yu.
于教授您好。
Welcome back to China.
欢迎回到中国。
Hello, Mr. Shi. Thank You.
石先生您好。谢谢。
I read your research
我读了你的研究
regarding the impact of financial limitations
关于财务限制的影响
on the financing behavior of public companies.
上市公司融资行为研究.
This differs from many domestic perspectives.
这与国内很多观点不同。
That's ancient thinking.
这是古老的思维。
This is getting quite long.
这已经变得相当长了。
My thinking has evolved this year.
今年我的想法发生了变化。
Accepting change is the right way.
接受改变 才是正确的方式。
I'm glad Guan Ji recruited you.
我很高兴管吉招募了你。
There are definitely plenty of opportunities
绝对有很多机会
for us to ask for your advice.
以便我们征求您的意见。
Mr. Shi, you flatter me.
石先生，你过奖了。
Yunchuang's future is limitless.
云创的未来不可限量。
We can learn from each other.
我们可以互相学习。
By the way,
顺便一提，
Some time ago, I read an article
前段时间看了一篇文章
"Zhu Xing Guo's Opinion on the Currency War."
《朱兴国 对货币战争的看法》。
The viewing angles are sharp.
视角很锐利。
His writing is insightful and deep. That's quite inspiring.
他的写作富有洞察力和深刻性。 这非常鼓舞人心。
You might want to take a look if you have time.
如果你有时间的话，你可能想看一下。
I remember the article vaguely.
我依稀记得那篇文章。
It's well written.
写得很好。
Cheers.
干杯。
Ladies and gentlemen, may I ask for your attention?
女士们先生们， 我可以请你们注意吗？
Today we gather here,
今天我们相聚在这里，
and all of you are old friends of Guan Capital.
你们 都是冠资本的老朋友了。
Towards the end of the year, I held this banquet
临近年底， 我举办了这场宴会
as a token of thanks for our sincere cooperation.
以感谢 我们的真诚合作。
We want to officially introduce new friends at once.
我们想立即正式介绍新朋友。
Our strategic advisor,
我们的战略顾问，
Mr Yu You, a finance professor.
余友先生，金融学教授。
Thank You.
谢谢。
Cheers.
干杯。
Enjoy the banquet.
享受宴会。
-Allow me to introduce... -No need.
-请允许我介绍一下... -不需要。
Yu You, you don't know
于友你不知道
he's been wanting to meet you for a long time.
他想见见你已经很久了。
I've never seen him so crazy about a girl.
我从来没有见过他 对一个女孩如此着迷。
You flatter me, Mr Shi.
石先生，你过奖了。
Okay.
好的。
We have completed this great task
我们已经完成了这个伟大的任务
and I've got a great expert for you.
我 为您找到了一位出色的专家。
My dad supports us, that's for sure.
我爸爸支持我们，这是肯定的。
Next, win the favor of the old people in Yunchuang.
接下来，赢得云庄老人们的青睐。
As for your father, do you want...
至于你的父亲，你想...
No need to rush, let's take it slow.
不必着急， 我们慢慢来。
Correct.
正确的。
Now we can call ourselves the three minions...
现在我们可以称自己为 三个小黄人了……
I'm not a lackey like you.
我不是像你一样的走狗。
Correct. We are like the Jiangcheng Triad,
正确的。我们就像 江城黑社会，
unstoppable with our intelligence.
以我们的智慧是无法阻挡的。
Cheers.
干杯。
Xing Zhou, where are you?
周星，你在哪里？
(The road is jammed. Give me a little more time.)
（路堵了， 再给我一点时间。）
(I'll be there as soon as possible.)
（我会尽快赶到。）
OK, I'll wait by the side of the road,
好的，我就 在路边等
so you don't need to look for me.
所以你不需要找我。
Ms. Zheng, long time no see.
郑老师，好久不见。
What are you doing here?
你在这里做什么？
Long time no see, Mr Zhang.
张先生，好久不见。
I'm here for an interview.
我是来面试的
I haven't had time to thank you properly
我还没来得及 好好感谢你
for the wonderful article you wrote for me last time.
谢谢你上次为我写的精彩文章。
How about I give you a ride?
我送你一程如何？
Mr. Zhang, you are too kind.
张先生，您太客气了。
You have a lot of experience
你有很多经验
which gives me room to shine.
这给了我发光的空间。
My boyfriend will be here soon.
我男朋友很快就会来。
No need to trouble you.
没必要麻烦你。
Well, take care of yourself.
嗯，照顾好自己。
Miss, are you alone?
小姐，你一个人吗？
Want me to give you a ride?
要我载你一程吗？
It was raining heavily and it was difficult to get a taxi.
雨很大，打到出租车很困难。
No, thank you. My boyfriend will be here soon.
不，谢谢。 我男朋友很快就会来。
Why are you standing here alone if you have a girlfriend?
你既然有女朋友了，为什么还要一个人站在这里？
Who says having a girlfriend means you can't stand here?
谁说有了女朋友 就不能站在这里？
Why Ms. Zheng is still here?
郑小姐怎么还在这里？
Didn't you prepare a car for him?
你没有给他准备一辆车吗？
He said someone picked him up.
他说有人接他。
How much longer, Xing Zhou?
还要多久，周星？
I am cold.
我好冷。
Maybe that person didn't have time?
也许那个人没有时间？
Right now, along this road,
此时此刻，沿着这条路，
and heavy rain,
和大雨，
difficult to get a taxi.
很难叫到出租车。
Step aside.
退到一边去。
I know it's raining hard, but I'm waiting for my boyfriend.
我知道雨下得很大， 但我在等我的男朋友。
Correct. I have a girlfriend. Thank you and good bye.
正确的。我有女朋友。 谢谢，再见。
It can't be him, right?
不可能是他吧？
Road.
路。
He was really waiting for his girlfriend.
他真的是在等他的女朋友。
I didn't think so
我不这么认为
he actually has a girlfriend.
他其实有女朋友。
I spoke to him several times by telephone
我和他通了几次 电话
and I think he's quite easy to get along with.
我觉得他很容易相处。
Maybe because he failed the interview today
也许是因为他今天面试失败了
and there are people trying to chat with him all day,
整天都有人想和他聊天，
Plus the weather is very cold,
再加上天气非常寒冷，
so he was a bit impatient.
所以他有些不耐烦了。
You seem quite worried about whether he has a girlfriend or not.
你似乎很担心 他有没有女朋友。
No.
不。
I think she is very beautiful,
我觉得她非常漂亮
and he is competent at his job.
他能胜任他的工作。
It's natural that he has a girlfriend.
有女朋友是理所当然的事。
So, you think she's beautiful
所以你觉得她很漂亮
and competent in their work?
并胜任他们的工作？
What we can be certain of is. Internally, they have high expectations
我们可以确定的是。在内部， 他们有很高的期望
if he will pass the position
如果他会通过这个职位
and got the position of deputy editor.
并获得副主编职务。
-Chen Sheng, I noticed something. -What's that?
——陈升，我注意到一件事。 -那是什么？
You seem more talented
看来你更有才华
become a gossip columnist instead of being my assistant.
成为一名八卦专栏作家 而不是当我的助手。
I'm sorry, Shu Yi.
对不起，舒仪。
Today it is raining heavily and the traffic jam is serious.
今天下着大雨，交通堵塞严重。
I'm stuck in traffic.
我遇到交通堵塞了。
-You must be cold. -I'm fine.
-你一定很冷吧。 -我很好。
How was your birthday today?
今天你生日过得怎么样？
Are you having fun?
你玩得开心吗？
My boyfriend didn't even celebrate with me. How can I be happy?
我男朋友甚至没有和我一起庆祝。 我怎样才能快乐？
Forgive me.
对不起。
Who is celebrating with you today?
今天谁和你一起庆祝？
Who else?
还有谁？
Xu Feng?
Xu Feng?
He even wears cologne now.
他现在甚至还喷古龙水。
The aroma is light and unique.
香气清淡而独特。
The taste is not bad.
味道还不错。
If you meet him again,
如果再遇见他
ask him what cologne he uses.
问他用什么古龙水。
I think it suits you too.
我想它也适合你。
How was the interview today?
今天面试怎么样？
Long story.
很长的故事。
Don't talk about it. Irritating.
别说这个了。 令人恼火。
Well, don't be mad, honey.
好吧，别生气，亲爱的。
Why didn't you answer my call?
你为什么不接我的电话？
I'm all yours after work.
下班后我就是你的了。
No telephones while working.
工作时不准接电话。
Stop by later.
稍后过来。
I'll make you long life noodles.
我给你做长寿面。
It doesn't matter. It is late
没关系。现在已经晚了
and you're not feeling well. Take it easy.
你感觉不舒服。 别紧张。
There will be many opportunities to make up for it.
会有很多机会 去弥补。
Why are you so considerate?
你为什么这么体贴？
It's because I love you, Stupid.
这是因为我爱你，傻瓜。
It's still your birthday.
今天仍然是你的生日。
Happy birthday, Xing Zhou.
周星，生日快乐。
Thank you darling.
谢谢你亲爱的。
I'm going home now.
我正在回家。
Hello. What is it?
你好。它是什么？
What?
什么？
I have to tell Mrs. Yi.
我得告诉易太太。
Where's my phone?
我的手机在哪里？
Hospital?
医院？
How could it be in the hospital?
怎么会在医院呢？
Was my phone stolen?
我的手机被偷了吗？
I was obviously holding my phone when I got into the car.
当我上车时，我显然拿着手机。
What is Xing Zhou doing in the hospital?
周星在医院做什么？
Is he sick?
他生病了吗？
Did he have a car accident?
他出车祸了吗？
He really is here.
他真的在这里。
License plate with repeating numbers.
车牌有重复的数字。
Better not mess with them.
最好别惹 他们。
He might be her friend.
他可能是她的朋友。
Visiting friends in the hospital at night is normal.
晚上去医院探望朋友是很正常的事情。